Guide to the Peter Newell Family Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Peter Newell: Visual Materials, 1879-1923; Series II; 295.1; (176 boxes) + 37 oil paintings
  - ILLUSTRATIONS FOR PERIODICALS
    - Collier's
      - Egan, Maurice Francis
        - "Pomp and Circumstance" (3/3), 1920 Sep 11 (Box 53, Folder 898-900)
        - "The Trimmings of Diplomacy" (2/3), 1919 Sep 6 (Box 53, Folder 901-902)
      - Stone, Melville E.
        - "Things Seen" (4/4), 1920 Feb 21 (Box 54, Folder 903-906)
      - Waldron, Webb
        - "Ersatz -- In Berlin" (2/2), 1919 May 24 (Box 54, Folder 907-908)
    - The Country Gentleman
      - Newell, Peter
        - Cover designs (2), ca. 1911 (Box 55, Folder 909)
        - "Old Saw Simpson", ca. 1920 (Box 55, Folder 910)
    - The Delineator
      - Newell, Peter - "Peter Newell's Movies"
        A series of illustrations meant to be cut out and folded to create action scenes. Each issue contained four "movies" which told a story.
        - No. 1, 1914 May (Box 55, Folder 911)
        - No. 2, 1914 May (Box 55, Folder 912)
        - No. 3, 1914 May (Box 55, Folder 913)
        - No. 4, 1914 May (Box 55, Folder 914)
        - No. 1, 1914 Jun (Box 55, Folder 915)
        - No. 3, 1914 Jun (Box 55, Folder 916)
        - No. 4, 1914 Jun (Box 55, Folder 917)
        - No. 1, 1914 Jul (Box 55, Folder 918)
        - No. 2, 1914 Jul (Box 55, Folder 919)
        - No. 3, 1914 Jul (Box 55, Folder 920)
        - No. 4, 1914 Jul (Box 55, Folder 921)
        - No. 1, 1914 Aug (Box 56, Folder 922-923)
        - No. 2, 1914 Aug (Box 56, Folder 924-925)
        - No. 3, 1914 Aug (Box 56, Folder 926-928)
        - No. 4, 1914 Aug (Box 56, Folder 929-930)
        - No. 1, 1914 Sep (Box 56, Folder 931)
        - No. 2, 1914 Sep (Box 56, Folder 932-934)
        - No. 3, 1914 Sep (Box 56, Folder 935)
        - No. 4, 1914 Sep (Box 56, Folder 936)
        - No. 1, 1914 Oct (Box 57, Folder 937)
        - No. 4, 1914 Oct (Box 57, Folder 938)
        - No. 1, 1915 Jan (Box 57, Folder 939)
        - No. 2, 1915 Jan (Box 57, Folder 940)
        - No. 4, 1915 Jan (Box 57, Folder 941)
        - No. 1, 1915 Apr (Box 57, Folder 942-943)
        - No. 2, 1915 Apr (Box 57, Folder 944)
        - No. 3, 1915 Apr (Box 57, Folder 945)
        - No. 4, 1915 Apr (Box 57, Folder 946-947)
        - Concepts not used, 1914-15 (Box 57, Folder 948-951)
    - Frank Leslie's Weekly
      - Newell, Peter
        - "Christmas in a Frontier Town: Shooting at the Wishbone", 1891 Dec 5 (Box 58, Folder 952)
    - Harper's Bazaar
      - Bacon, Dolores Marbourg
        - "When Mary Ellen Left Home" (4/5), 1903 Nov (Box 58, Folder 953-959)
      - Johnson, Burges
        - "Santa Claus" (not used), 1905 Jan (Box 59, Folder 960)
      - Stuart, Ruth McEnery
        - "The Snow-Cap Sisters" (headpiece), 1897 Dec 25 (Box 59, Folder 961)
      - Newell, Peter: "The Biddleby Family"
        - [1] "The Latest Arrival at Newport", 1894 Aug 11 (Box 59, Folder 962)
        - [3] "The Biddleby Family at Newport (they bathe at Easton's Beach)", 1894 Aug 18 (Box 59, Folder 963)
        - [4] "The Biddleby Family at Newport (they attend a tennis tournament)", 1894 Sep 1 (Box 59, Folder 964)
        - [6] "The Biddleby Family run over to Block Island", 1894 Sep 15 (Box 59, Folder 965)
        - [9] "The Biddleby Family at Boston" [concept sketch], 1894 Oct 6 (Box 59, Folder 966)
        - [10] "The Biddleby Family in New York", 1894 Oct 13 (Box 59, Folder 967)
        - Concept sketches not developed, [1894] (Box 59, Folder 968-969)
      - Newell, Peter: "Columbian Exposition Series"
        This series of drawings from the 1893 World's Columbian Exposition at Chicago was published in both Harper's Bazaar and Harper's Weekly. All sketches and drawings are filed under Harper's Weekly below.
      - Newell, Peter: other work
        - Comics, 1884 (Box 60, Folder 970-980)
        - Comics, 1885 (Box 60, Folder 981-1004)
        - Comics, 1886 (Box 61, Folder 1005-1009)
        - Comics, 1887 (Box 61, Folder 1010-1012)
        - Comics, 1888 (Box 61, Folder 1013-1017)
        - Comics, 1889 (Box 61, Folder 1018-1025)
        - Comics, 1890 (Box 61, Folder 1026-1027)
        - Comics, 1893 (Box 61, Folder 1028-1032)
        - Comics, 1894 (Box 62, Folder 1033-1038)
        - Comics, 1895 (Box 62, Folder 1039-1049)
        - Comics, 1896 (Box 62, Folder 1050-1058)
        - Comics, 1897 (Box 62, Folder 1059-1063)
        - Comics, 1899 (Box 62, Folder 1064-1066)
        - Comics, 1900 (Box 62, Folder 1067)
        - [Numbers not used] (Box 62, Folder 1068-1073)
        - Comics, 1908 (Box 62, Folder 1074)
        - Comics, 1885 (Box 63, Folder 1075)
        - Comics, 1887 (Box 63, Folder 1076)
        - Comics, 1891 (Box 63, Folder 1077)
        - Comics, 1892 (Box 63, Folder 1078-1079)
        - Comics, 1894 (Box 63, Folder 1080-1081)
        - Comics, 1895 (Box 63, Folder 1082)
        - Comics, 1896 (Box 64, Folder 1083-1085)
        - Comics, 1897 (Box 64, Folder 1086)
    - Harper's Monthly Magazine
      - Bangs, John Kendrick
        - "Pinkerton's Nightmare" (1/1), 1901 Oct (Box 65, Folder 1087)
      - Brown, Cambray
        - "Barnaby's Fox Hunt" (3/3), 1922 Jan (Box 65, Folder 1088-1090)
        - "The Time Clock in the Taj Mahal" (3/3), 1921 Feb (Box 65, Folder 1091-1093)
      - Butler, Ellis Parker
        - "The Quarrelsome Club" (3/3), 1916 Nov (Box 66, Folder 1094-1096)
      - Brubaker, Howard
        - "Greeks Bearing Gifts" (2/3), 1917 Nov (Box 67, Folder 1097-1098)
        - "Norwayfarers" (3/3), 1914 Nov (Box 67, Folder 1099-1101)
        - "Thoughts on Pedestrians" (3/3), 1916 Aug (Box 68, Folder 1102-1104)
      - Clouston, J. Storer
        - "The Hereditary Cleaner" (4/7), 1904 Sep (Box 68, Folder 1105-1108)
      - Colton, Arthur Willis
        - "The Little Cruise of the Violetta" (5/6), 1903 Feb (Box 69, Folder 1109-1113)
        - "Torre Ananias" (3/4), 1903 May (Box 69, Folder 1114-1116)
      - Copley, Frank B.
        - "Murphy and My Mother-in-law" (½), 1921 Aug (Box 70, Folder 1117)
      - Curly, Roger
        - "The Tale of a Tail-Spinner" (3/3), 1920 Jun (Box 70, Folder 1118-1120)
        - "Three on an Island" (3/3), 1920 Aug (Box 70, Folder 1121-1123)
      - Curtiss, Philip
        - "The Crocodile's Half-Sister" (6/6), 1920 May (Box 71, Folder 1124-1129)
        - "The Fancy Skater of Melonmerang" (4/5), 1921 May (Box 72, Folder 1130-1133)
        - "The Left-Handed Piccolo Player" (4/5), 1920 Dec (Box 72, Folder 1134-1137)
        - "The Postmaster-General of Mindanao" (5/6), 1920 Oct (Box 73, Folder 1138-1142)
        - "The Waving Palm and the Blue Lagoon" (4/5), 1921 Jan (Box 74, Folder 1143-1146)
      - Fife, George Buchanan
        - "In All Her Glory" (2/3), 1903 Jun (Box 75, Folder 1147-1148)
      - Fisk, May Isabel
        - "Calling on the Doctor (A Monologue)" (3/3), 1916 Feb (Box 75, Folder 1149-1151)
      - Guiterman, Arthur
        - "Afternoon Tea" (3/4), 1918 Jun (Box 76, Folder 1152-1154)
        - "The Ballad of the True Sportsman" (3/3), 1918 Jan (Box 76, Folder 1155-1157)
        - "The Conqueror (An Algonquin Legend)" (3/3), 1917 Jun (Box 77, Folder 1158-1160)
        - "The Origin of Species" (2/2), 1917 Feb (Box 77, Folder 1161-1162)
        - "The Rival Bootblacks" (2/2), 1921 Nov (Box 77, Folder 1163-1164)
      - Hallet, Richard Matthews
        - "The Mountain and Mahomet" (5/5), 1920 Nov (Box 78, Folder 1165-1169)
      - Herold, Don
        - "Bon Voyaging the Burglar" (2/3), 1916 May (Box 78, Folder 1170-1171)
      - Irwin, Wallace
        - "Silence" (6/6), 1917 Jul (Box 79, Folder 1172-1177)
        - "Starch and Gasoline" (3/3), 1917 Jan (Box 80, Folder 1178-1180)
      - Johnson, Burges
        - "A Knight of the Table-Cloth" (3/3), 1919 Feb (Box 81, Folder 1181-1183)
        - "The Sincere Salad-Dresser" (2/3), 1916 Sep (Box 81, Folder 1184-1185)
      - Joubert, Wilfred A.
        - "A Vanilla-Bean Comedy" (6/6), 1918 Nov (Box 82, Folder 1186-1191)
      - Mitchell, Ruth C. and Sanborn Young
        - "Old Man Hicks Was Right" (2/3), 1919 Sep (Box 83, Folder 1192-1193)
      - Moitoret, Anthony F.
        - "The First and Only Cruise of the Caoutchouc, 1919 Jan (Box 83, Folder 1194-1196)
      - Neidig, William J.
        - "The Camel from Home" (6/6), 1917 Oct (Box 84, Folder 1197-1202)
      - Newell, Peter
        - Cover designs for January 1893, 1892 (Box 85, Folder 1203-1205)
        - Comics, 1893 (Box 85, Folder 1206-1208)
        - Comics, 1894 (Box 85, Folder 1209-1210)
        - Comics, 1895 (Box 85, Folder 1211-1214)
        - Comic, 1896 (Box 85, Folder 1215)
        - Comics, 1898 (Box 85, Folder 1216)
        - Comics, 1899 (Box 85, Folder 1217-1220)
        - Comics, 1900 (Box 85, Folder 1221-1224)
        - Comics, 1901 (Box 86, Folder 1225-1235)
        - Comics, 1903 (Box 86, Folder 1236-1237)
        - Comics, 1904 (Box 86, Folder 1238-1242)
        - Fables, 1904 (Box 86, Folder 1243-1244)
        - Comics, 1905 (Box 86, Folder 1245-1246)
        - Fables, 1905 (Box 86, Folder 1247-1251)
        - Fables, 1906 (Box 86, Folder 1252-1253)
        - Comics, 1895 (Box 87, Folder 1254)
        - Comics, 1899 (Box 87, Folder 1255)
        - Comics, 1900 (Box 87, Folder 1256)
        - Comics, 1924 (Box 87, Folder 1257)
      - Paine, Albert Bigelow
        - "An Excursion in Memory" (2/3), 1917 Mar (Box 88, Folder 1258-1259)
        - "The Meanness of Pinchett" (3/3), 1918 Apr (Box 88, Folder 1260-1262)
        - "Mrs. Tumulty's Hat" (3/3), 1916 Jul (Box 88, Folder 1263-1265)
        - "Reforming Julius" (3/3), 1920 Dec (Box 89, Folder 1266-1268)
        - "Reserved Seats" (3/3), 1919 Aug (Box 89, Folder 1269-1271)
        - "A Thwarted Pygmalion" (3/3), 1918 Mar (Box 90, Folder 1272-1274)
      - Pape, Lee
        - "Night Flower" (2/3), 1916 Jan (Box 90, Folder 1275-1276)
      - Partridge, Edward Bellamy
        - "Fate and Fifteen Hundred Dollars" (6/6), 1916 Dec (Box 91, Folder 1277-1282)
      - Pottle, Emery
        - "A Mistake in the Horoscope" (6/6), 1917 Nov (Box 92, Folder 1283-1288)
      - Ravenal, Beatrice
        - "Something to Remember" (4/6), 1920 Jan (Box 93, Folder 1289-1292)
      - Robinson, Eloise and John Froome, Jr.
        - "Dead Dog" (6/6), 1918 Sep (Box 94, Folder 1293-1298)
      - Russell, John
        - "Foul Deeds" (5/6), 1918 Jan (Box 95, Folder 1299-1303)
      - Scott, Arthur P.
        - "Yvette" (1/3), 1920 Apr (Box 95, Folder 1304)
      - Steele, Wilbur Daniel
        - "Clay and the Cloven Hoof: A Story in Two Parts, Part I" (5/5), 1919 Oct (Box 96, Folder 1305-1309)
        - "Clay and the Cloven Hoof: A Story in Two Parts, Part II" (6/6), 1919 Nov (Box 97, Folder 1310-1315)
        - "Mr. Scattergood and the Other World" (6/6), 1918 Jul (Box 98, Folder 1316-1321)
      - Wells, Carolyn
        - "The Re-Echo Club" (3/6), 1917 Jul (Box 99, Folder 1322-1324)
        - "The Rime of Lady May" (3/3), 1918 Dec (Box 99, Folder 1325-1327)
    - Harper's Weekly
      - Newell, Peter: Chicago World's Fair
        The series describes the experiences of the Johnson family at the 1893 World's Columbian Exposition. The final two installments were published in Harper's Bazaar but all of the drawings are filed here together.
        - No. 1 "The Johnson Family Visits the Great White City", 1893 Jul 15 (Box 100, Folder 1328)
        - [2] "The Johnson Family at the Midway Plaisance", 1893 Aug 5 (Box 100, Folder 1329)
        - [3] "The Jackson Family Visits Jackson Park in the Evening", 1893 Aug 12 (Box 100, Folder 1330)
        - [4] "The Johnson Family Visits the Dahomian Village", 1893 Aug 19 (Box 100, Folder 1331)
        - [5] "The Johnson Family in Cairo Street", 1893 Aug 26 (Box 100, Folder 1332)
        - [6] "Mr. Johnson Hires a Roller Chair", 1893 Sep 2 (Box 100, Folder 1333)
        - [7] "The Johnson Family in the Esquimaux Village", 1893 Sep 9 (Box 100, Folder 1334)
        - [8] "The Johnson Family Visits Lady Aberdeen's Irish Village and Blarney Castle", 1893 Sep 16 (Box 100, Folder 1335)
        - [9] "The Johnson Family Visits the Village of the South Sea Islanders", 1893 Sep 23 (Box 100, Folder 1336)
        - [10] "The Johnson Family Take a Gondolo Ride", 1893 Sep 30 (Box 100, Folder 1337)
        - [11] "The Johnson Family Witness the Drill of the Life-Saving Crew", 1893 Oct 7 (Box 100, Folder 1338)
        - [12] "The Johnson Family Visits the Lap Village", 1893 Oct 14 (Box 100, Folder 1339)
        - [14] "The Johnson Family Visits the Javanese Village", 1893 Nov 11 (Box 100, Folder 1340)
        - "The Johnson Family Visits an Ostrich Farm," [unpublished?], [1893] (Box 100, Folder 1341)
        - "The Johnson Family Inspects the Viking Ship" (published in Harper's Bazaar ), 1893 Nov 4 (Box 100, Folder 1342)
        - "In the Last Days of the Fair the Johnson Family Happen upon the Reproductions of Aztec Ruins," (published as "Yucatan Ruins" in Harper's Bazaar ), 1893 Nov 18 (Box 100, Folder 1343)
      - Newell, Peter: Paris Exposition
        Another series of drawings covered "Uncle Jeff Pettingill" and his observations during the Exposition Universelle Internationale de 1900.
        - I. "Rafe, my boy...", 1900 Jun 2 (Box 101, Folder 1344-1345)
        - II. "What's that, Rafe?", 1900 Jun 16 (Box 101, Folder 1346-1347)
        - III. "Rafe, we beat the French...", 1900 Jun 23 (Box 101, Folder 1348-1349)
        - IV. "I say, Rafe...", 1900 Jul 14 (Box 101, Folder 1350-1351)
        - V. "Ah, you ugly heathen...", 1900 Jul 21 (Box 101, Folder 1352-1353)
        - VI. "What's that feller up to...", 1900 Aug 4 (Box 101, Folder 1354)
        - [VII.] "Lie down, Rafe...", 1900 Aug 11 (Box 102, Folder 1355-1356)
        - [VIII.] "By Jimminy, Rafe...", 1900 Aug 11 (Box 102, Folder 1357-1358)
        - IX. "Uncle Jeff...", 1900 Aug 18 (Box 102, Folder 1359-1360)
        - X. "Whew, but the air's hot...", 1900 Aug 25 (Box 102, Folder 1361-1362)
        - XI. "The old lady...", 1900 Sep 1 (Box 102, Folder 1363-1364)
        - XII. "One day, near the Algerian...", 1900 Sep 15 (Box 102, Folder 1365-1366)
      - Newell, Peter: other work
        - Comics, 1885 (Box 103, Folder 1367-1371)
        - Comics, 1886 (Box 103, Folder 1372)
        - Comics, 1887 (Box 103, Folder 1373-1374)
        - Comics, 1894 (Box 103, Folder 1375)
        - Front page, 1895 (Box 103, Folder 1376)
        - Cover, 1908 (Box 103, Folder 1377)
        - Political conventions, 1912 (Box 103, Folder 1378-1383)
        - Comics, 1894 (Box 104, Folder 1384-1388)
        - Comics, 1908 (Box 104, Folder 1389)
        - "Edward Makes a Vow" (front page), 1903 Mar 21 (Box 105, Folder 1390)
        - "Signor Marconi" (front page), 1903 Mar 28 (Box 105, Folder 1391)
        - "William the Teuton" (front page), 1903 Mar 7 (Box 105, Folder 1392-1393)
      - Twain, Mark
        - "The $30,000 Bequest" (15/13), 1904 Dec (Box 106, Folder 1394-1405)
        - "The $30,000 Bequest" (15/13), 1904 Dec (Box 107, Folder 1406-1408)
    - Harper's Young People
      - Bangs, John Kendrick
        - "Bunkey, Monkey and Jimmieboy" (1/1), 1895 Mar 19 (Box 107, Folder 1409)
      - Herrick, Christine
        - "A Candy Party" (1/1), 1894 Mar 6 (Box 107, Folder 1410)
      - Kozbi, E. Karl
        - "A Lottery for Life" (½), 1891 Nov 3 (Box 107, Folder 1411)
      - Newell, Peter
        - Comics, 1884 (Box 108, Folder 1412-1413)
        - Comics, 1885 (Box 108, Folder 1414-1420)
        - Comics, 1886 (Box 108, Folder 1421-1422)
        - Comics, 1887 (Box 108, Folder 1423-1424)
        - Comic, 1888 (Box 108, Folder 1425)
        - Comics, 1889 (Box 108, Folder 1426-1428)
        - Comic, 1890 (Box 108, Folder 1429)
        - Comic (child mounting horse), ca. 1890
          See: Oversize, Folder 3345
        - Comic, 1893 (Box 108, Folder 1430)
        - Comics, 1895 (Box 108, Folder 1431-1433)
        - Comic, 1896 (Box 108, Folder 1434)
        - Comics, 1886 (Box 109, Folder 1435-1436)
        - Comic, 1892 (Box 109, Folder 1437)
        - Comic, 1893 (Box 109, Folder 1438)
        - Comics, 1894 (Box 109, Folder 1439-1440)
      - Pyle, Katherine
        - "The Circus Parade" (1/5), 1892 Sep 20 (Box 109, Folder 1441)
      - Ralph, Julian
        - "The Careless Boy who Lost His Head" (2/3), 1892 Nov 22 (Box 109, Folder 1442-1443)
    - The Ladies' Home Journal
      - Newell, Peter
        - Designs for "Alice in Wonderland Bedquilt", 1905 Sep (Box 110, Folder 1444-1448)
        - Designs for "Alice in Wonderland Sofa Pillows", 1905 Aug (Box 110, Folder 1449-1455)
    - The Ladies' World
      - Newell, Peter
        - "Needle-dee and Needle-dum", 1914 (Box 110, Folder 1456)
    - Life
      - Newell, Peter
        - Comic, 1889 (Box 110, Folder 1457)
        - Comic, 1891 (Box 110, Folder 1458)
        - "New Years Eve, 1892", 1892 Dec 29 (Box 110, Folder 1459)
        - Comic, 1901 (Box 110, Folder 1460)
        - Comics, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 1461-1462)
        - [The diva and the potted palm] (Box 110, Folder 1463-1468)
    - McClure's Magazine
      - Browne, Porter Emerson
        - "As To Melting Pots" (1/1), 1918 Mar (Box 111, Folder 1469)
        - "The Bolsheveakness of Bolshevism" (3/3), 1919 Jul (Box 111, Folder 1470-1472)
        - "E Pluribus Unum" (1/1), 1917 Nov (Box 111, Folder 1473)
        - "The Neutral" (1/5), 1916 May (Box 112, Folder 1474)
        - "The New War" (1/1), 1919 Aug (Box 112, Folder 1475)
        - "Patriotocracy" (1/?), 1918 Dec (Box 112, Folder 1476)
        - "Plain Bill" (2/?), 1917 Oct (Box 112, Folder 1477-1478)
        - "Please Right Face" (4/5), 1917 Jul (Box 113, Folder 1479-1482)
        - "Scars and Stripes" (1/5), 1916 Aug (Box 113, Folder 1483)
        - "Uncivil War" (3/6), 1918 May (Box 114, Folder 1484-1486)
        - "Uncle Sham!" (2/5), 1916 Apr (Box 114, Folder 1487-1488)
        - "We'll Dally 'Round the Flag, Boys!" (3/5), 1916 Oct (Box 115, Folder 1489-1491)
      - Field, Salisbury
        - "Home Sweet Home" (2/3), 1919 Dec (Box 115, Folder 1492-1493)
      - Unidentified author
        - "Love-Mad Lucy" (4/?), n.d. (Box 116, Folder 1494-1497)
    - Metropolitan
      - Newell, Peter
        - Various fables, 1905 (Box 117, Folder 1498-1500)
    - St. Nicholas
      - Rivers, Pearl
        - "Little Nut People", 1892 (Box 117, Folder 1501-1502)
      - Newell, Peter
        - "Inanimate Things Animated", n.d. (Box 117, Folder 1503-1504)
        - Comic, 1892 (Box 117, Folder 1505)
        - "Inanimate Things Animated", 1892 (Box 117, Folder 1506-1508)
        - "Inanimate Things Animated", 1893 (Box 118, Folder 1509-1517)
        - Comic, 1903 (Box 118, Folder 1518)
    - Woman's Home Companion
      - Caroll, R. Elliott
        - "Pa Sez" (1/1), 1908 Aug (Box 119, Folder 1519)
      - Newell, Peter
        - "The Only Safe Course" (1/1), 1908 Dec (Box 119, Folder 1520)
    - The Youth's Companion
      - Foster, Edna A.
        - "The Children's Circus" (3/4), 1902 Oct 9 (Box 119, Folder 1521-1523)
      - Unidentified author
        - "A Girl and an Opportunity" (1/?) (Box 119, Folder 1524)
        - "A Place for William" (1/?), n.d. (Box 119, Folder 1525)
  - ILLUSTRATIONS FOR CALENDARS
    - Publication of these calendars has not been verified with the exception of the calendar for 1910.
      See also: Series I, Box 15 for proofs (?) of a 1903 calendar and the complete 1910 edition.
      See also: Series I, Box 16 as well as Box 122 for the 1904 Rogers Peet calendar.
    - Calendar for 1903, page designs, [1902] (Box 120, Folder 1526-1536)
    - Calendar for 1905, cover, [1904] (Box 120, Folder 1537)
    - Calendar for 1906, cover, [1905] (Box 120, Folder 1538)
    - Calendar for 1910
      - Cover designs, [1909] (Box 120, Folder 1539-1542)
      - Page design, [1909] (Box 120, Folder 1543)
  - ILLUSTRATIONS FOR CORPORATE PROJECTS
    - Charles E. Hires and Company
      - Sketches for root beer advertisements, ca. 1906 (Box 121, Folder 1544-1555)
      - "Josh Slinger" on cloud, ca. 1906 (Box 122, Folder 1556)
    - J. P. Primley
      - Sketches for California Fruit Chewing Gum advertisements, [1894] (Box 122, Folder 1557)
    - Proctor and Gamble
      - Ivory Soap advertisement, n.d. (Box 122, Folder 1558)
    - Rogers, Peet and Company
      - Calendar for 1904
        - Cover design, 1903 (Box 122, Folder 1559)
        - Page designs, 1903 (Box 122, Folder 1560-1563)
  - UNIDENTIFIED OR UNPUBLISHED DRAWINGS
    Publication of these drawings has not been verified, though some have annotations indicating that they were at least submitted for publication. They are arranged by format: Comic Strips; Comics; Headpieces and Covers; Story Illustrations; and Other Drawings and Sketches.
    - Comic strips
      - "The Bingles", n.d. (Box 123, Folder 1564)
      - "Dye Innoculation", n.d. (Box 123, Folder 1565-1567)
      - "An Easter Hat Pin", n.d. (Box 123, Folder 1568)
      - "Easter Manna", n.d. (Box 123, Folder 1569)
      - "The Jolly Trolley", n.d.
        See: Oversize, Folder 3346
      - "The Maiden and the Gallant Bear" (Box 123, Folder 1570)
      - "Mr. Enos Whiffletree", n.d. (Box 123, Folder 1571-1572)
      - "The Musician Wins a Bride", n.d. (Box 123, Folder 1573-1574)
      - "The Nuts", n.d. (Box 123, Folder 1575-1576)
      - "Sampson Simms", n.d. (Box 123, Folder 1577-1578)
      - "Simple Simon", n.d. (Box 123, Folder 1579)
      - "Spikeville", n.d. (Box 123, Folder 1580-1581)
      - "Wesley in Cipherland"
        See: Oversize, Folder 3347
      - Untitled, n.d. (Box 123, Folder 1582)
    - Comics
      - African-American themes, ca. 1880-99 (Box 124, Folder 1583-1608)
      - Holiday themes
        - Christmas, n.d. (Box 125, Folder 1609-1616)
        - "A Blunder Buss Under the Mistletoe", 1900
          See: Oversize, Folder 3348
        - Fourth of July, n.d. (Box 125, Folder 1617-1620)
        - New Year, 1908, n.d. (Box 125, Folder 1621-1622)
        - Valentine's Day, n.d. (Box 125, Folder 1623-1631)
      - Smoking and drinking themes (Box 126, Folder 1632-1638)
      - Comics, undated, [1880s] (Box 127, Folder 1639-1654)
      - Comics, 1884 (Box 128, Folder 1655-1656)
      - Comics, ca. 1884 (Box 128, Folder 1657-1658)
      - Comics, 1888 (Box 128, Folder 1659-1663)
      - Comics, 1889 (Box 128, Folder 1664)
      - Comics, 1890 (Box 128, Folder 1665-1667)
      - Comics, 1891 (Box 128, Folder 1668)
      - Comics, 1893 (Box 128, Folder 1669-1671)
      - Comics, 1896 (Box 128, Folder 1672)
      - Comics, 1887 (Box 129, Folder 1673)
      - Comics, 1888 (Box 129, Folder 1674-1675)
      - Comics, 1890 (Box 129, Folder 1676-1677)
      - Comics, 1891 (Box 130, Folder 1678-1680)
      - Comics, 1892 (Box 130, Folder 1681)
      - Comics, 1893 (Box 130, Folder 1682)
      - Comics, ca. 1896 (Box 130, Folder 1683)
      - Comics, 1900 (Box 130, Folder 1684-1685)
      - Comic, 1888 (Box 131, Folder 1686)
      - Comic, 1890 (Box 131, Folder 1687)
      - Comic, 1891 (Box 131, Folder 1688)
      - Comic, 1897 (Box 131, Folder 1689)
      - Comic, 1900 (Box 131, Folder 1690)
      - Comics, n.d. (Box 132, Folder 1691-1696)
      - Comics, n.d. (Box 133, Folder 1697-1701)
      - Comic (alligator theme), n.d.
        See: Oversize, Folder 3349
      - Comics, undated 19th century (Box 134, Folder 1702-1720)
      - Comics, undated 19th century (Box 135, Folder 1721-1736)
      - Comics, undated 19th century (Box 136, Folder 1737-1750)
      - Comics, undated 20th century (Box 137, Folder 1751-1775)
      - Comics, undated 20th century (Box 138, Folder 1776-1796)
      - Comics, undated 20th century (Box 139, Folder 1797-1806)
      - Comics, undated 20th century (Box 140, Folder 1807-1814)
      - Comics, undated 20th century (Box 141, Folder 1815-1825)
    - Headpieces and Covers
      - July 4th cover, n.d. (Box 142, Folder 1826-1828)